Guide to the Office of the Comptroller records, 1874-2002 RG0064
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- Trust fund ledgers and journals, ca. 1920-1986; RG0064 Series 2; 13.5 Linear feet
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (C), 1954 - 1971; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Accounts 1300, starting with the letter C. Updates on these accounts range from between 1954 - 1971. (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (D), 1946 - 1971; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Account 1300, starting with the letter D. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1971. (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (E-F), 1948 - 1971; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Accounts 1300, starting with the letter E and F. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1970. (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (G), 1953 - 1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Accounts 1300, starting with the letter G. Updates on these accounts range from between 1953 - 1969. (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (H-J), 1946 - 1971; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Accounts 1300, starting with the letter H, I, and J. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1971. (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (K-L), 1946 - 1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Accounts 1300, starting with the letters K and L. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (M), 1947 - 1971; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Account 1300, starting with the letters M. Updates on these accounts range from between 1947 - 1971. (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (N-O), 1947 - 1970; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Accounts 1300, starting with the letters N and O. Updates on these accounts range from between 1947 - 1970. (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (P-Q), 1946 - 1971; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Account 1300, starting with the letter P-Q. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1971. (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (R-S), 1946 - 1972; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Account 1300, starting with the letter R-S. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1972. (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (Scottish Rite), 1956 - 1972; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Account 1300 and referring to funds set up by the Scottish Rite. Updates on these accounts range from between 1956 and 1972. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (T-V), 1946 - 1971; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Account 1300, starting with the letter T-V. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1971. (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Restrictive Income - Account 1300 (W-Z), 1946 - 1971; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Account 1300, starting with the letter W-Z. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1971. (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Agency Fund - Account 1400, 1946 -1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Account 1400. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Unrestricted Income (A-B), 1946-1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Unresticted Income, starting with the letter A-B. Account numbers are unorganized, but generally fall between 1500 and 1599. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Unrestricted Income (C), 1946 - 1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Unresticted Income, starting with the letter C. Account numbers are unorganized, but generally fall between 1500 and 1800. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Unrestricted Income (D-E), 1946 - 1971; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Unresticted Income, starting with the letter D-E. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Unrestricted Income (F-G), 1946 - 1969 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Unrestricted Income (H-K), 1946 - 1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Unresticted Income, starting with the letter H-K. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Unrestricted Income (L-O), 1946 - 1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Unresticted Income, starting with the letter L-O. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Unrestricted Income (P-R), 1946 - 1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Unresticted Income, starting with the letter L-O. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Unrestricted Income (S), 1946 - 1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Unresticted Income, starting with the letter S. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Unrestricted Income (T-Y), 1946 - 1969; Rehoused from a binder titled "Restrictive Income - Sep. 1, 1946 - June 30, 1969." Originally listed in Acc. 855 - Item 4. Records ordered alphabetically, reflecting how they were originally ordered. Includes information about accounts all labeled under Unresticted Income, starting with the letter T-Y. Updates on these accounts range from between 1946 - 1969. (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Funded Accounts - Administration, 1962 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "administration" and refer to funded accounts with account numbers starting with 700. Accounts refer to a variety of different scholarships, program funds, and building funds from across The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 1)
    Fund raising; Endowments
  - Funded Accounts - Columbian College of Arts and Sciences, 1961 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Columbian" and refer to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 701." Accounts refer to a variety of different scholarships, grants, program funds, research and academic programs, concert series, and building funds and other funds that were overseen by the Columbian College of Arts and Sciences. (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Funded Accounts - Education, 1965 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Education" and refer to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 702-". Accounts refer to a variety of programs including internships, regionally-based fellowships, nationally-based fellowships, student teaching programs, foundations, workshops, and grants related to education at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Funded Accounts - Engineering, 1960 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "administration" and refer to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 703-." Accounts refer to a variety of different scholarships, program funds, internship programs, and research funds regarding engineering from across The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 4)
    Engineering; Fund raising; Endowments
  - Funded Accounts - General Studies, 1967 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Gen. Studies" and refer to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 704-." Accounts refer to a variety of different scholarships, administrative program, conference funds, course funds, research programs, institutues, internships, workshops, student teaching programs, academic programs hosted by NASA, the FBI, and the Pentagon, and programs related to nursing, the military, and other programs within The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Funded Accounts - Government, 1961 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "administration" and refer to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 705-". Accounts refer to a variety of purposes including centers, institutes, and programs related to federal departments hosted at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Funded Accounts - Graduate Council, 1961 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Grad. Council" and refer to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 706-". Accounts refer to a variety of purposes including centers, fellowships, institutes, and partnership programs related to the Graduate Council at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 7)
    Universities and colleges -- Graduate work -- Administration; Endowments; Fund raising
  - Funded Accounts - Law School, 1955 - 1970; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Law" and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 707-". Accounts refer to a variety of internships, institutes, centers, material funds, endowments, foundations, workshops, conferences, and grants related to The George Washington University Law School. The law school was previously known as the "National University School of Law at The George Washington University" and the "National Law Center" at the time these records were being kept. (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Funded Accounts - Medicine, 1959 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Medicine" and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 708-". Accounts refer to a variety of purposes including funds, programs, research, workshops, courses, seminars, and chairships related to the School of Medicine at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Funded Accounts - Public Affairs, 1965 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Public Affairs" and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 709-". Accounts refer to a variety of purposes including the Institute of Sino-Soviet Studies, Ford Grant Programs, and other grants under the Public Affairs program at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Funded Accounts - Summer Sessions, 1966 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Summer Sessions" and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 710-". Accounts refer to a variety of purposes including NDEA Advanced Study in English and the Summer English Institute at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Funded Accounts - Airlie, 1966 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Airlie" and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 713-". Accounts refer to a variety of purposes including research for the U.S. Public Health Service (USPHS), programs for handicapped and deaf students filed under "Airlie" at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Funded Accounts - Peace Corps, 1966 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Peace Corps" and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 714-". Accounts refer to the Peace Corps programs at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 13)
    Endowments; Fund raising
  - Funded Accounts - Hospital, 1958 - 1970; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Law" and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540". Accounts refer to a variety of purposes, including programs, organizations, clincs, residencies, grants, funds, and estates related to The George Washington University Hospital. (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Funded Accounts - Library, 1963 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Law" and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540 750-". Accounts refer to various book funds kept by Lisner Library at The George Washington University. Lisner Library was the forerunner to the current libraries at GWU. (Box 9, Folder 15)
    Lisner Library; Endowments; Fund raising
  - Funded Accounts - Miscellaneous, 1964 - 1970; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Misc." and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540". Accounts refer to a variety of purpopses including annual giving campaigns, trust funds, endowed funds, conferences, grants, federal work-study programs, and other accounts at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Funded Accounts - Agency, 1961 - 1969; Files rehoused from a binder titled "Funded." Files in this folder all came under a tab titled "Agency" and refers to funded accounts with account numbers starting with "540". Accounts refer to a variety of purposes including the School of Education, Women's Board Gift Shop, Law Library, and GW Faculty Alumni Club at The George Washington University. (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1953; Includes accounts receivable entries for the fiscal months of September to December, 1953. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 1)
    Journals (accounts)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1954; Includes accounts receivable entries for the year of 1954. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1955; Includes accounts receivable entries for the year of 1955. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1956; Includes accounts receivable entries for the year of 1956. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1957; Includes accounts receivable entries for the year of 1957. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month, largely in the form of quarterly account updates, and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1958; Includes accounts receivable entries for the year of 1958. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1959; Includes accounts receivable entries for the year of 1959. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1960; Includes accounts receivable entries for the year of 1960. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month, mostly in quarterly account updates, and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1961; Includes accounts receivable entries for the year of 1961. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month, mostly in quarterly account updates, and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1961 - 1962; Includes accounts receivable entries for the fiscal year of 1961-62. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month, mostly in quarterly account updates, and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1962 - 1963; Includes accounts receivable entries for the fiscal year of 1962-63. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month, mostly in quarterly account updates, and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Accounts Receivable Journal, 1963 - 1964; Includes accounts receivable entries for the fiscal year of 1963-64. Includes updated account totals for schools, institutions, and miscellaneous purchases within the university, including tuitions, fees, housing, and college budgets. Journal was originally filed as Acc. #855 and rehoused from its original binder. Accounts are organized by month, mostly in quarterly account updates, and kept in their original order as kept by the Office of the Comptroller. (Box 10, Folder 12)